

Junior Software Engineer | Instructional Assistant

0410 485 482 | mark.mekhayl@gmail.com | Sydney, Australia | https://github.com/Lozlink https://www.linkedin.com/in/mark-mekhayl-393834137/ | https://markmekhayl.vercel.app

SUMMARY

A junior developer with 6 years' of prior experience in corporate sales across varying industries. Combining problem solving skills, technical aptitude and and the transferrable skills developed through sales & marketing roles, I have experience in understanding stakeholder needs and would love to apply that creatively in software engineering projects

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSIVE

General Assembly
March 2023 - June 2023

BACHELOR OF BUSINESS & COMMERCE

Western Sydney University 2013-2017

SKILLS

Javascript, JQuery

Ruby, Ruby on Rails

SQL

HTML, CSS, SASS

React.js

Node.js

Sinatra

Jest

Git

GitHub

API Integration/Axios

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROJECTS

SPRITE KNIGHT

- Collaborative web-based game utilizing Node.js, Express.js, and Postgresql
- Built entirely as a Single Page application
- Deployed with Fly.io

BUDGIET

- A budget tracking tool built using React, Express.js & Postgresql
- Sass & CSS implementation
- API integration using Axios

EXPERIENCE

INSTRUCTIONAL ASSISSTANT - SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSIVE

General Assembly

March 2023 - Present

- Provided code review & feedback for a group of 22 of students on a daily basis, as well as 4 major projects feedback.
- Orchestrated tutorials among various tech stacks
- Focus on improving coding best practices
- Provide general and technical instructional support for the students in the cohort

SALES & MARKETING MANAGER

Sunshade Shutters & Blinds

February 2021 - May 2022

- Managed sales growth by targeting key markets effectively.
- Led targeted marketing campaigns to key demographics via analysis
- Used Data Analysis for market segmentation

SALES EXECUTIVE

Alsco Australia

November 2019- February 2021

- Proactively targeted demographics through analysis to deliver successful sales results.
- Managed Stakeholder relationships both internally and externally.
- Established relationships with several high profile businesses and worked in tangent with account managers.